Ioshua Korner-Godsiff

A1501 / 1-17 Elsie St, Burwood, NSW, 2134

□ 0408 125 562 | ☑ josh.godsiff@gmail.com | □ joshgodsiff | ☐ joshgodsiff

About Myself _____

I'm Josh. I'm a software developer with around 9 years of commercial experience, and I currently live and work in Sydney.

My expertise is in functional programming, service-oriented cloud architectures, large-scale data processing pipelines, and web development. I'm also passionate about privacy, civil liberties, the environment, and education.

I spent most of 2020 working on my own startup in the digital identity space. However, due to some significant life events (she's adorable - I will show you so many photos) I'm putting that on the back-burner for the forseeable future.

For my next role I'm looking for something where I can step up and take on more responsibility. In particular, a role where I can work across both software development and product management would be ideal.

I graduated from the Australian National University in 2014 with a Bachelor of Computer Science (Honours) - one of their most challenging and selective degrees.

At university I focused on large scale parallel and distributed systems; various machine learning, data mining and AI techniques; and a healthy dose of pure theory and mathematics.

Skills

Programming Haskell, Scala, Java, JavaScript, Python, SQL

Document / Data Formats HTML & CSS, XML, Avro, JSON

Databases MySQL, PostgreSQL, Kafka, ElasticSearch

Libraries & Frameworks React, Hedgehog, Lens, MTL

Cloud Platforms AWS, GCP

Operating Systems Windows, Ubuntu Linux, MacOS **Tools & Software** VSCode, JetBrains IDEs, Git, Terraform

Soft Skills Agile, Product Management, Mentoring, Kanban, Scrum

Experience _____

Sydney, Australia Volv October 2021 - June 2022

STAFF SOFTWARE ENGINEER

At Voly I worked as a senior - and later staff - software engineer, nominally on the backend team, although in practice my role encompassed the full stack from the web front-end, to the backend, to server administration, cloud infrastructure, databases and security.

I was responsible for maintaining and building upon the initial go-to-market MVP software that the company had procured - written in TypeScript using NestJS and GraphQL, and using Shopify as a backend for most of the ecommerce aspects.

I was also responsible for facilitating a company wide consultation and requirements gathering process to define the scope of a replacement backend system that was fit for purpose for the company's mid and long term growth and product goals.

My team had begun work implementing this new backend, using Haskell, Postgres and Hasura (a Postgres-to-GraphQL API layer), as well as Terraform for managing infrastructure on Google Cloud. Unfortunately, due to the global downturn, my role was impacted by a round of layoffs so we were not able to complete this work.

On the softer-skill side, I also had a lot of fun mentoring some junior and mid-level frontend developers, and bringing my team up to speed working in an agile Kanban system.

PrezzeeSydney, Australia

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

March 2021 - September 2021

At Prezzee, I was responsible for integrating the company's chosen CMS (Kentico Kontent) into their website and their app's web front-end, in order to enable non-technical employees to manage content.

I was also responsible for building out a large chunk of their web UI component library, and integrating that into the website and app as part of a site redesign that was happening at the same time as the CMS was being rolled out.

The work was largely done in ReScript (a compiles-to-JavaScript functional language) and React. There was also integration work involving Next.js, and infrastructure work in Terraform.

As a part of that work, I helped onboard and upskill several junior and mid-level engineers onto the project, and was in practice running the dev team a lot the time as the lead / head-of-frontend was often busy with other work.

I also introduced several new agile practices that resulted in my team being one of the most consistent and accurately performing (in terms of estimates vs reality) teams in the company.

1Self Sydney, Australia

Co-Founder February 2020 - Present

As a co-founder I worked across all functions of the business, with a particular focus on software development, product management, and legal and compliance issues.

Netscout (formerly Arbor Networks)

Sydney, Australia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

January 2017 - January 2020

At Netscout I worked as part of an agile team to deliver scalable data processing pipelines that power a suite of analytics tools and services which are used by both their customers, and their sales and support teams.

My team and I were responsible for almost all aspects of these pipelines, including development, deployment, monitoring, end-to-end-testing, and working with our product and delivery management team to clarify goals and scope work.

I primarily worked in Haskell for development, with some forays into Scala (legacy pipelines), Ruby & Terraform (deployment & infrastructure tooling), Python (ML code, scripting), and even occasional bits of C and JavaScript.

I learned an incredible amount, especially about what it takes to develop and deploy stable, scalable, and maintainable solutions. I also greatly enjoyed some of my secondary duties, which included leading internal workshops on Haskell and functional programming, as well as mentoring interns in some fundamental computer-science concepts.

General Dynamics Mediaware

Canberra, Australia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

October 2015 - December 2016

At Mediaware I worked as part of an agile team to help deliver mission critical video processing software to our defence and broadcast customers around the globe.

My primary responsibility was leading the development and design of the web-based user interfaces to our core products. These used a purpose-built Python + KnockoutJS framework, as many of the products had real-time constraints that required a careful interaction model. Later in the role I also introduced a more traditional AngularJS + Python stack for a separate project.

My secondary responsibilities included working with senior architects on system design, liaising with key stakeholders to gather requirements and feedback, and producing reports to inform business level decision making.

I also dove into the main server applications (C/C++) from time to time to implement the relevant endpoints and data sources for the UI.

Welcomer

Canberra, Australia October 2014 - July 2015

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Canberra, Australia

Australian National University

February 2012 - June 2015 (Part time)

Tutor

Oxide Interactive

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER

Canberra, Australia

January 2010 - September 2010

Zoo Advertising

WEB DEVELOPER (CONTRACTOR)

Canberra, Australia March 2009 - September 2009

The Stavridis Group

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER

Canberra, Australia

November 2008 - February 2009

Education_

Australian National University

Canberra, Australia

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE (HONOURS) - FIRST CLASS HONOURS

2009 - 2014

The Bachelor of Computer Science (Honours) is a four year undergraduate degree taught in English. The degree is a research-focused professional program for exceptional students who have an interest in undertaking research in an industry or academic environment. It is expected that students will graduate with First Class Honours.

Bachelor of Computer Science (Honours) students are expected to maintain a superior distinction average in order to remain in the degree.

An academic transcript is available upon request.

General Assembly Sydney, Australia

PRODUCT MANAGEMENT - 1 WEEK INTENSIVE

2019

A one week intensive course on product management, covering topics such as the product lifecycle, hypothesis validation, customer interviews, personas, feature prioritisation, competitor research, minimum viable products, product roadmaps, metrics, sketching, wireframes, usability testing, and agile.

Community Involvement.

International Conference on Functional Programming

Berlin, Germany

ATTENDEE

Lambda Jam Sydney, Australia ATTENDEE, SPEAKER

2017, 2018, 2019, 2021, 2022

In 2018 I gave a talk on "The Human Side of Haskell"

PyConAU Melbourne, Australia

ATTENDEE

Functional Programming Meetup

Canberra & Sydney, Australia

GROUP MEMBER

2016 - Present

Lean Beer Meetup

Canberra & Sydney, Australia

FOUNDING MEMBER

2016 - Present

A fortnightly meetup on Agile, Lean, project management, software development, & startups

Presentations

Lambda Jam

Sydney, Australia

THE HUMAN SIDE OF HASKELL 2018

✓ YouTube - https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z0vkQLLUVGw